

 \searrow

robin9029@gmail.com

+91-8056044372

Q

Bengaluru, India

github.com/robin9029

SKILLS

python

SQL

RviceScript

Text Processing Using Python

NLP Concepts

Machine Learning

Docker

Flask

HTML

CSS

LANGUAGES

English

Full Professional Proficiency

Hindi

Full Professional Proficiency

INTERESTS

Sports

Yoga

music

travelling

Photo editing

Ravi Shekhar Kumar

Sr. Software Engineer

Having Experience in automation and solution building through algorithmic intelligence and Cognitive computing capabilities with overall experience 6.7+ years in I.T Industry. Have working exposure to the core functions of a Banking & Healthcare Domain .Aiming to obtain proficient position to enhance my skills for Personal/Professional & growth of the organization.

EDUCATION

Computer Science & Engineering Dayananda sagar College of Engineering

08/2008 - 09/2012

Bangalore,Karnataka-75.26%

PROJECTS

Wipro's Artificial Intelligence (AI) and automation platform, Holmes (10/2017 – Present)

- Cognitive Search AI- Application uses elasticsearch utilizing its fast search engine capabilities for building customer use case & deployment & maintaining bot
- Chatbots -Used rivescript library of python as the processing engine to create flows for different use cases of chatbots. Used open-source rasa-NLU for Intent Identification and Entity Extraction in texts.
- Classifiers Used Machine Learning Classification libraries to create a classification algorithm with around 80% base accuracy and added rules to increase it further
- Integrations As all bots are build on python as the core language and flask as the web service to host them, created a few use cases by integrating chatbots with search engine to make a FAQ/ Question Answer bot. Integrated ServiceNow with classifier to automate support group classification of tickets.

Health Plan Services , Wipro (07/2016 - 09/2017)

- Health Plan Services is a insurance Provider in USA Aquired by wipro .As a part of Mainframe Core team we are validating all the transaction which are coming into the System. Based on requirement will have to doing analysis, design code and provide fix the existing codes along with unit testing & documentations
- Skill used : Mainframe Technologies

LBG Credit Management(Loans Migration) HCL (11/2013 – 07/2016)

- Loans Migration Project in which all the Halifax loans where moved to the new platform called CLP. We have to provide with all the data mapping from our platform to new platform & whichever Loans Account is Active have to put the State of Account as repaid by providing the Current Balance as zero
- PPI Target on Modeling Halifax loan, Once the Loan has been Repaid the accounts is maintained for the some years & then deleted from the system. Loan Document still after deletion of the Account from System.
- Skill used : Mainframe Technologies

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sr. Software Engineer Wipro Technologies

07/2016 – Present

Wipro is an Indian multinational corporation that provides information technology, consulting and business process services. It is headquartered in Bangalore, Karnataka, India

Software Engineer HCL Tecnologies

11/2013 - 07/2016

HCL Technologies Limited is an Indian multinational information technology service and consulting company headquartered in Noida, Uttar Pradesh, India

CERTIFICATES

IBM Certified Application Developer - Watson V3 (10/2019)

IBM Certified Database Associate -- DB2 9 Fundamentals (11/2015)

5+ Udemy Courses